Guide to the Stanford University, Department of History, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of History, records
1975-1981
SC0257
Stanford University. Department of History.
1.25 Linear feet
Collection includes specifications, planning documents, design documents, meeting minutes, correspondence, memoranda, clippings and other records relating to the reconstruction of the "History Corner" of the Quadrangle. Architects for the project were Stone, Marraccini and Patterson / Esherick Homsey Dodge and Davis.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, History Department, 1981.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Associated Materials
Architectural drawings for this project are housed under the building number (01-200) within the Stanford University Archives Architectural Drawings Collection.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes specifications, planning documents, design documents, meeting minutes, correspondence, memoranda, clippings and other records relating to the reconstruction of the "History Corner" of the Quadrangle. Architects for the project were Stone, Marraccini and Patterson / Esherick Homsey Dodge and Davis.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Department of History.; College buildings --Designs and plans.; Specifications.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Academic program, drafts (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1976-77 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and memos, 1975-79 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and memos, 1976-79 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and memos, 1978-79 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Design Development Outline Specifications, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Facilities, Office Record re history corner project, 1976-77 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - History Corner Reconstruction Schematic Document, May 11, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History Corner Reconstruction, Working Draft, April 7, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - History Corner Survey Report, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Individual space requirements (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Initial Program Statement and Quad Reconstruction pamphlets, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Meeting Reports, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Meeting Reports, 1977-Mar. 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Reports, April-Dec. 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Reports, Jan.-Aug. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Reports, Sept. 1979-80 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Memo re relocating history department with office plans, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous material re architects (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Moving plans for faculty, 1975-76 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Notes, agenda, minutes, reports, etc., 1975-76 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Punch list, Oct. 15, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Relocation quote, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Space Program for History Corner (1-200) Reconstruction, first draft, Feb. 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Space Program for History Corner (1-200) Reconstruction, final drafts, May 1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Space Program for Margaret Jacks Hall, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Assorted drawings and plans (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Furniture inventory, Ryan Lab, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Interior furnishings budget, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)